DAN KLEIN: Now that we have filtering
in hand, we can look at another
important idea for speeding things up.
And in fact, this idea is very,
very quick to implement once
you know about filtering.
And that is the idea of ordering.
So int he idea ordering, we've got
choices in our backtracking search.
We've got a choice of which
variable comes first.
And for a given variable, we have a
choice of which value comes first.
The most important one is
picking your variable.
Which variable should I choose next?
And the basic idea is we're going to
choose the variable that has the
fewest legal values left
in its domain.
How do we know how many values
are left in its domain?
Fortunately, we're running forward
checking, or arc consistency.
And so as a result, every unassigned
variable has a count
associated with it.
So for example, in this Australia
case, we might assign red here.
And then we might assign green here.
And the question is, what's next?
Well probably we should continue on with
this heavily constrained node in
the south because it only
has one value left.
It has to be blue.
It would've been a mistake to hop on
over to the other side of the graph
and try to assign over here, or
Tasmania, or something like that.
So the idea here is when you're
confronted with a choice of variables,
and some are very, very free and some
are very heavily constrained, you
should take the one that's most
constrained, which the minimum
remaining values.
So the question is, why do we do
the min rather than the max?
Why are we making our lives hard
and going down the scary path?
You've already seen in the demo why.
But the basic idea here is you have to
do every variable at some point.
You might as well do the hard ones right
now at the beginning so that the
backtracking is not expensive because
you're still near the top of the tree.
OK, that's the important idea for
minimum remaining values.
Do the heard variables first because
you're eventually going to have to do
them, and you shouldn't procrastinate.
This is also called fail-fast
ordering.
Because if there's going to be a problem
with these variables, you want
discover now at the top of the tree,
not way at the bottom of the tree
where backtracking is
exponentially worse.